Ayodele Ajayi



ayoinc@gmail.com



linkedin.com/in/ayoinc



https://containercode.club

Summary

A bright, talented and ambitious DevOps/SysOps / Security / Application specialist with a strong technical background who possesses self-discipline and the ability to work with the minimum of supervision. Having exposure to a wide range of technologies & able to play a key role in diagnosing hardware, software problems, analyse network logs for security and to ensure that quality solutions meet business objectives. Possessing a good team spirit, deadline orientated and having the ability to organize and present complex solutions clearly and accurately.

Experience



Site Reliability Engineer

The Rank Group plc

Mar 2020 - Present (9 months +)

Implementing globally used processes and procedures, monitoring solutions, and building a Site Reliability. Increasing operational up-time of websites and technical services.

DevOps Engineer

Adjoint Inc.

Aug 2019 - Mar 2020 (8 months)

Ops for FinTech / Smart Ledger Solution

IT Engineer

OpenAsset

Jan 2018 - Aug 2019 (1 year 8 months)

Supporting OpenAsset Digital Asset Management Software in Cloud and OnPremise Clients

System Analyst (IT Contractor)

Indivior

Mar 2016 - Jan 2018 (1 year 11 months)

Senior IT Analyst

SC Johnson

Aug 2015 - Mar 2016 (8 months)

📘 IT Support Technician / Multimedia

New Testament Church of God

Dec 2012 - Jun 2015 (2 years 7 months)

IT Technician and Music IT.

IT and System Support Technician

Guardian Newspaper Nigeria Mar 2011 - Apr 2012 (1 year 2 months) Contract / Temporary Position

Education



Harvard University

Certificate, Cybersecurity: Managing Risk in the Information Age 2017 - 2018

Centred on:

- * Using Cyber risk management to mitigate Cyber attacks
- * Identifying cyber threats to crucial business systems and data
- * Vulnerability assessment on business systems, networks and data
- * Building a cybersecurity leadership plan
- * Generating questions to determine money invested in a business cybersecurity
- * Distinguish the legal and compliance risk for an organisation
- * Propose an incident response plan to prepare an organization in the event of an attack.
- * Designing and implementing a risk mitigation strategy.

The Open University

Professional Development, Cyber Security for Small and Medium Businesses 2016 - 2016

Designed for System Analysts and Network Engineers

Readynez

Professional Development, Project Management 2016 - 2016 PRINCE2

Capital College

Diploma, Business, Management, Marketing, and Related Support Services 2012 - 2013

Association of Business Executives

New Horizons Computer Learning Centre

Dip. Multimedia Technology, Multimedia Technology 2012 - 2012

Adobe Photoshop, Flash CS6, Indesign, Dreamweaver & Adobe Flash

Dalewares Institute of Technology

National Innovative Diploma, Multimedia Technology 2009 - 2012

Multimedia Technology

HP Online Learning Center

High School, Wireless Networking 2007 - 2008 Hewlett Packard Online Distance Learning Center

Tomoriware Computer Institute

Diploma, Computer Installation and Repair Technology/Technician 2006 - 2007
Computer Repairs and Maintenance

Oshodi Comprehensive High School

High School, Senior Secondary School Certificate 1996 - 2002 Mathematics, English Language, Physics, Chemistry, Geography, Yoruba Language

Licenses & Certifications

- National Ordinary Diploma National Board For Technical Education
- **PRINCE2 Foundation** APMG International PRINCE209092016
- National Innovative Diploma National Board for Technical Education NID001012009
- Windows Server 2012 Administration Udemy
- Active Directory & Group Policy 2012 Lab Udemy
- in Securing Windows 10 LinkedIn
- Kali Linux for Penetration Testing LinkedIn
- introduction to Ethical Hacking LinkedIn
- **Cyber Security Fundamentals The Open University** FutureLearn
- Fundamentals of Network Security Alison Free Online Learning

- Cyber Security for Small and Medium Enterprises: Identifying Threats and Preventing Attacks Deakin University FutureLearn
- Cyber Security Economics Technische Universiteit Delft 459b5b32b36044f496007512fac769fd
- Windows Server Administration Certified 2017 Microsoft
- Networking Fundamentals Certified 2017 Microsoft
- Security Fundamentals Certified 2017 Microsoft
- Cybersecurity: Managing Risk in the Information Age Harvard University
 11394878
- AWS Certification Exam Readiness Workshop: AWS Certified Solutions
 Architect Professional Global Knowledge
- Diploma in DevOps Engineering Kubernetes, Docker and Google Cloud Alison Free Online Learning 1696-3957634
- Google Cloud Platform Fundamentals: Core Infrastructure Coursera SAWDZXH5ZUNN
- Essential Cloud Infrastructure: Foundation Coursera

 EKZT7BTDS3HF
- Essential Cloud Infrastructure: Core Services Coursera NBHVU462A5DM
- Elastic Cloud Infrastructure: Scaling and Automation Coursera
 JNWN43VSV4SP
- Reliable Cloud Infrastructure: Design and Process Coursera
 WFTMDYPS43D3
- Architecting with Google Compute Engine Specialization Coursera

CE5Y2QCDF6P2

- Serverless Architecture Lynda.com
- OpenShift for Absolute Beginners Udemy UC-LE7D8ASA
- in AWS DevOps: Continuous Docker Deployment to AWS Fargate from GitLab LinkedIn

 Aa6k0sMrU_FHDDLQLJjMYqc90iPs
- Docker for Java Developers LinkedIn
 AasDfmtpfhhwn_dF9pRGxkcm2V39
- Google Cloud Platform (GCP) For Techs Simplilearn
- PRINCE2® Foundation Certification Training Firebrand Training
- Automation with Ansible II: Ansible Tower (DO409) Lynda.com
- Learning the Elastic Stack Lynda.com
- Site Reliability Engineering: Service-Level Agreements and Objectives Lynda.com
- Developing and Delivering Software with Docker Lynda.com

Skills

Continuous Integration • Information Security • Agile & Waterfall Methodologies • ITIL • Project Management • Web Development • Strategic Planning • Infrastructure • Virtualization • Linux System Administration